Let's get started writing some queries.
فلنبدأ بكتابة بعض الاستعلامات.
First, we're going to generate a list of
أولًا سننتِج قائمة
all the orders that Parch and Posey has ever received.
بجميع الطلبات التي تلقاها بارش وبوسي يومًا.
It's a simple but valuable way to learn a bit more about the company.
إنها طريقة سهلة، ورفيعة القيمة رغم ذلك، لتعلُّم بعض المعلومات الإضافية حول الشركة.
Parch and Posey records their orders in a table called Orders.
يسجِّل بارش وبوسي طلباتهما في جدول باسم Orders،
That table contains all the columns you see here,
وبتضمن ذلك الجدول جميع الأعمدة التي ترونها هنا
each of which corresponds to some attribute and order.
بحيث يتوافق كلٌ منها مع سمة ما وطلب ما.
Each order has a unique ID,
لكل طلب معرِّف مميز
so that it can be referenced and a time stamp to indicate when that order was placed.
حتى يمكن الرجوع إليه، وطابع وقت ليشير إلى الوقت الذي وُضع فيه ذلك الطلب.
It also contains quantity sold and revenue generated for each type of paper ordered.
يتضمن الجدول أيضًا الكمية المباعة والربح الناتج لكل نوع تم طلبه من الأوراق.
In order to generate the list of all orders,
لكي ننشئ قائمة بجميع الطلبات،
we'll write a SELECT statement.
سنكتب عبارة SELECT.
Think of a SELECT statement as
انظروا لعبارة SELECT كما لو كنتم
filling out a form to get the results you're trying to get.
تملؤون نموذجًا للحصول على النتائج التي تحاولون الحصول عليها.
The form has a set of questions like,
يتضمن النموذج مجموعة من الأسئلة مثل:
what data do you want to pull from?
ما البيانات التي تريد سحبها؟
And which elements of that data set do you want to pull?
وأيّ عناصر مجموعة البيانات هذه تريد أن تسحب؟
These questions are structured in the same order every time.
هذه الأسئلة مبنية بنفس الترتيب في كل مرة،
Some of them are mandatory and others are optional.
بعضها أساسي والبعض الآخر اختياري.
When writing out the SELECT statement,
عند كتابة عبارة SELECT
each of these questions is represented by a single word like SELECT or FROM.
يتم تمثيل كلٍ من هذه الأسئلة بكلمة مفردة، مثل SELECT أو FROM،
These words are called clauses.
وتُسمى هذه الكلمات روابط.
The FROM clause tells the query what data to use.
يخبر الرابط FROM الاستعلام ما البيانات التي عليه استخدامها.
Here, we're looking at the Orders table.
سنركز هنا على الجدول Orders،
So I'll write that in after FROM.
لذا سأكتب ذلك بعد الكلمة FROM.
The SELECT clause tells the query which columns to read from that table.
يخبر الرابط SELECT الاستعلام أيّ الأعمدة عليه أن يقرأ من ذلك الجدول.
Column names are separated by commas with no comma needed after the last column name.
يتم الفصل بين أسماء الأعمدة بفاصلات، مع عدم الحاجة إلى وجود فاصلة بعد آخر اسم لعمود.
You can also select all of the column names using
يمكنكم أيضًا اختيار جميع أسماء الأعمدة
Select with an asterisk where the asterisk means all.
باستخدام Select، مع وضع علامة نجمية حيث تعني تلك العلامة تحديد الجميع.
People typically say this as select star.
عادةً ما يعبر الناس عن هذه النجمة بقولهم إنها "نجمة الاختيار".
Both the SELECT and FROM clauses are mandatory.
كلا الرابطين SELECT وFROM أساسي،
You'll include them in every query you write as part of this course.
وسوف تقومون بتضمينهما في كل استعلام تكتبونه كجزء من هذه الدورة التدريبية.
If you do not include both of them,
إذا لم تقوموا بتضمين كليهما
you'll get an error message instead of the desired results.
فستجدون رسالة خطأ بدلًا من النتائج المطلوبة.
When I click run, the database will execute this query and return the results,
حين أنقر فوق run ستنفِّذ قاعدة البيانات هذا الاستعلام، وتستعيد النتائج
every row in the Orders table showing all available columns.
بحيث يعرض كل صف في الجدول Orders جميع أعمدة المتغيرات.
Now that you've seen this,
الآن وبما أنكم قد رأيتم هذا،
you already have enough knowledge to do something valuable.
فقد امتلكتم بالفعل معرفة كافية للقيام بشيء ما ذي قيمة.
You can read a table,
يمكنكم قراءة جدول،
and if you'd like,
وإذا أردتم
export your results to view them in another application like Excel.
فصدِّروا نتائجكم لعرضها في تطبيق آخر مثل Excel.